A Guide to the Governor Terry McAuliffe, Policy Office, Records, 2002; 2006-2008; 2010-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)
Library of Virginia
- II. Subject Files, 2004; 2006-2008; 2010-2018 (bulk 2014-2017)., Extent: 8.68 cubic feet (14 boxes). (Box 11-24)
  - Subseries II.A. Anna Healy James, Policy Office Director, 2004; 2006-2007; 2010-2016., Extent: 1.7 cubic feet (3 boxes) (Box 11-13)
    - House Appropriations Committee Meeting, 20 October 2014. (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - House Democratic Caucus, February-March 2014. (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Housing, undated. (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Hurricanes, August 2014. (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Indigent Care, undated. (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Inter-agency Task Force on Payroll Fraud, 2014. (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Joint Advisory Board of Economists (JABE), 2014. (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Local Government Budget and Finance Success, 7 February 2014. (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Lottery, September 2015. (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Marriage Equality, 2014. (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - Medicaid, 2014-2015. (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - Medicaid Expansion, February 2014. (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Medicaid Expansion, April 2014. (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Medicaid Expansion, May-July 2014. (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Medicaid Expansion, August 2014-January 2016. (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - Medicaid Expansion, February 2016. (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Medicaid Forecast, 17 October 2014. (Box 11, Folder 47)
    - Medicaid Private Option, 2014. (Box 11, Folder 48)
    - Natural Gas, 2014. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - No State Budget, 2004; 2006-2007. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Ozone, 2014. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Partnership for Food, Farms, or Families (First Lady Dorothy McAuliffe), December 2014. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Pipeline (Atlantic Coast Pipeline Project), 2014. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Provider Assessment Workgroup, 2015. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Provider Tax, 2014. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Social Services, 2014. (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - State Corporation Commission (SCC), July 2016.. (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Strategic Priorities, 1 May 2014. (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Uber, November 2014. (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - VCU Health System, October 2014. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Veterans, undated. (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Virginia529, July 2014. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Virginia Association for Community Conflict Resolution, July 2015. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Biosciences Health Research Corporation, 22 October 2015. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Virginia Board for People with Disabilities, August 2014. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Department of Health Professions, 2014. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Virginia First Cities, 30 October 2015. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Hospital and Healthcare Advocacy Council (VHHAC), 31 August 2015. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Secretary of Education, Report on Academic-Year Governor's Schools Funding Formula Study, 1 October 2014. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Women's Health, August 2014. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Workforce, 2014. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Subseries II.B. Jennifer Wicker, Deputy Legislative Director, 2008; 2013-2015 (bulk 2014)., Extent: 2.0 cubic feet (2 boxes) (Box 14-15)
    This subseries is housed in two (2) boxes and arranged alphabetically by subject. The processing archivist created folder titles for loose records. On 14 January 2014, Governor Terry McAuliffe announced the appointment of Jennifer Wicker as Deputy Legislative Director. Wicker's policy areas included education, health and human services and workforce. Wicker served previously as Legislative Coordinator in the office of Richmond Mayor Dwight C. Jones. She also worked as Legislative Assistant to Delegates Viola Baskerville and Jennifer McClellan. Wicker left the McAuliffe administration in March 2015. See also Series I.B.1 - Legislative Files (Policy Analysts), Jennifer Wicker.
    Notable subjects include: Richmond 2015 UCI Road World Championships (September 19-27, 2015); Standards of Learning (SOL); Medicaid; and Abortion Clinic Facilities.
    - Abortion Clinic Rules, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Accreditation/Accountability Public Schools, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Accredited Public Schools with Warning (3 years), undated. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Adult High School Programs (Regulations, 8 VAC 20-30 and 8 VAC 20-680), June 2014. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - American Association of University Women (AAUW) of Virginia, 15 October 2014. (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Apollo Education Group, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Back to School, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Ban-the-Box, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Bioscience, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - 100 Black Men of Central Virginia, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Body by Jake, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - 2014 Budget Requests, April 2014. (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Cabinet Weekly Reports, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Career Coaches, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Carl Perkins Career and Technical Education Act, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Casey Family Programs, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 15a)
    - Child Care in Virginia (1 of 3), 2014. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Child Care in Virginia (2 of 3), 2014. (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Child Care in Virginia (3 of 3), 2014. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Children's Cabinet Launch, 11 August 2014. (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Children's Cabinet Meeting, 20 October 2014. (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Children's Cabinet Meeting, 17 November 2014. (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Children's Cabinet Meeting, 15 December 2014. (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Comcast/Cox, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Contacts, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB)/Financial Exploitation, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Council of Independent Colleges in Virginia, 19 November 2014. (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Council of State Senior Business Officers (CSSBO) 2014-2016 Budget Briefing, 17 December 2014. (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Cover Virginia Campaign, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Decision Briefs, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Deputies Meetings, November 2014. (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Donors Choose, September 2014. (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Early Childhood Education - Workgroup on Quality (Virginia Commission on Youth), 16 September 2014. (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Early Childhood "Face-Out" undated. (Box 14, Folder 33)
    - Early Childhood Education, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 34)
    - Early Childhood Initiatives, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 35)
    - Ebola, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Education, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Education (Notes), 27 August 2014. (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Education Briefing to Governor Terry McAuliffe, 22 August 2014. (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Education Contacts (Nationally), 2014. (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - K-12 Education Funding, 26 August 2014. (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Education Priorities, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Education Priorities Announcement, 22 September 2014. (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Education Regulations, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Education Summit, House of Delegates, 11 November 2014. (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Education Superhighway, 3 June 2014. (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Elementary and Secondary Education Act (ESEA) of 1965, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Executive Orders/Directives, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - Family Access to Medical Insurance Security (FAMIS) Enrollment Event, 19 September 2014. (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Fairfax County Child Care Assistance and Referral (CCAR) Program, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - Fannie Mae CEO Phone Call, 25 September 2014. (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - First Lady's Initiatives, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - Forensic Science, undated. (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Fort Monroe Authority, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 54)
    - Foster Care, undated. (Box 14, Folder 55)
    - Future Meetings, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 56)
    - Generation Ready, 2 October 2014. (Box 14, Folder 57)
    - 2014 Governor's Fellows Program, June-July 2014. (Box 14, Folder 58)
    - Governor's Task Force for Local Government Mandate Review, 2014-2015. (Box 14, Folder 59)
    - Governor's Task Force on Prescription Drug and Heroin Abuse Executive Order Signing, 26 September 2014. (Box 14, Folder 60)
    - Governor's Task Force on Prescription Drug and Heroin Abuse, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 61)
    - Greater Richmond SCAN, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 62)
    - Grow by Degrees, 30 October 2014. (Box 14, Folder 63)
    - H1B Visas/Universities, 2014. (Box 14, Folder 64)
    - HB 1009 Bill Signing (Workforce), 2014. (Box 14, Folder 65)
    - HHR - Pam Kestner Meeting, 18 September 2014. (Box 14, Folder 66)
    - Healthcare Access (see also Medicaid), 2014. (Box 14, Folder 67)
    - Healthcare-PCP Bump (Medicaid), 2014. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Health Regulations, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Higher Ed/Deadlines, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Hospice Facilities, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Impaired Nurses, September-October 2014. (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC) Meeting, 8 December 2014. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Licensure of Abortion Facilities, September 2014. (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Local Government Budget Presentation, 15 August 2014.. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Mediation Centers (Christine Poulson), 4 August 2014. (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Medicaid, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Medicaid 101 and Reforms, Cindi B. Jones, Director of the Virginia Department of Medical Assistance Services, 18 September 2014. (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Medicaid Townhalls, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Memorandums (Miscellaneous), 2014. (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Mental Health (Call with former Congressman Patrick J. Kennedy), 10 March 2014. (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Microsoft, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Military Occupation Specialties (MOS)/NVCC Event, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - State Senator John Miller, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - National Council for Adoption, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - National Governors Association (NGA)/Education, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - News, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Old Dominion University (ODU) Meeting, 19 December 2014. (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Opportunity Education Institution (OEI), 2014. (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Physical Education Program Guidelines, undated. (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Policy Meetings, July-August 2014. (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Portsmouth - Jordan Bridge Budget Amendments, 2015. (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Pre-K Development Grant, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Pre-School Programs, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - President's Budget for Fiscal Year 2015, 4 March 2014. (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Prisoner Re-entry, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Proclamations, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Project Discovery of Virginia, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Protocol for Virginians, 2008. (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Public Charter Schools, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Read, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Regional Teacher of the Year, 17 September 2014. (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Regulatory Review, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Restoration of Rights, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Revenue Reports, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Bruce Richardson, Henrico County Schools, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Richmond 2015 UCI Road World Championships, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Richmond 2015 UCI Road World Championships, State Coordinating Committee, 24 August 2014. (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Richmond, Shockoe Bottom, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - School Calendar, undated. (Box 15, Folder 43)
    - School Improvement, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 44)
    - Sexual Assault, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 45)
    - Shareholders' Asks, undated. (Box 15, Folder 46)
    - Southside Child Care Development Center, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 47)
    - Standards of Learning (SOL), 2014. (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Standards of Learning (SOL), Bill Signing, 11 June 2014. (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Strategy Meetings, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 50)
    - Student Loan Debt Forgiveness, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 51)
    - Substance Abuse Services Council Annual Report, 1 October 2014. (Box 15, Folder 52)
    - Tier II: State Fiscal Regulations, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 53)
    - To Do-High Priority, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 54)
    - To Do-Low Priority, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - Training Centers, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - Unaccompanied Children, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - University of Mary Washington (UMW) Meeting, 19 December 2014. (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - University of Virginia, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 59)
    - Urban Policy Report, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 60)
    - VCU Health System Cabinet Briefing, 2 October 2014. (Box 15, Folder 61)
    - Veterans, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 62)
    - Veterans Summit, 3 November 2014. (Box 15, Folder 63)
    - Virginia Business Higher Education Council, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 64)
    - Virginia Capitol Foundation (VCF), 2014. (Box 15, Folder 65)
    - Virginia Community College System (VCCS), 2014. (Box 15, Folder 66)
    - Virginia Community Economic Network, 27 August 2014. (Box 15, Folder 67)
    - Virginia Department of Behavioral Health and Developmental Services (DBHDS), Western State Hospital Efficiency Study, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 68)
    - Virginia Department of Social Services (VDSS), Quaterly Agency Meeting, 7 July 2014. (Box 15, Folder 69)
    - Virginia Higher Education Research Summit, 9 June 2014. (Box 15, Folder 70)
    - Virginia Indian Commemorative Commission, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 71)
    - Virginia Municipal League (VML), Fall Conference, 5-7 October 2014. (Box 15, Folder 72)
    - Virginia Preschool Initiative, 2013-2014. (Box 15, Folder 73)
    - Virginia School Boards Association, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 74)
    - Virginia Secretary of Health and Human Resources (HHR) Fall Retreat, 16 October 2014. (Box 15, Folder 75)
    - Virginia State Council of Higher Education (SCHEV), Research Summit, 9 June 2014. (Box 15, Folder 76)
    - Virginia STEAM Academy, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 77)
    - Virginia Tech, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 78)
    - Virginia Virtual Academy, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 79)
    - Virginia Workers' Compensation Commission, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 80)
    - Wirick, Glenn, 3 June 2014. (Box 15, Folder 81)
    - Workforce, 2014. (Box 15, Folder 82)
  - Subseries II.C. Jennie Moline O'Holleran, Senior Policy Advisor to the Governor/Policy Director, 2013-2017., Extent: 1.7 cubic feet (3 boxes) (Box 16-18)
    This subseries is housed in three (3) boxes. The records were in no discernible order; a large number of records were loose and not foldered. The processing archivist imposed an alphabetical arrangement by subject. Jennie Moline O'Holleran served as Senior Policy Advisor to the Governor and Policy Director from October 2015 to January 2018. O'Holleran served as Deputy Secretary of Education from January 2014 to October 2015, focusing on preK-12 education issues. Prior to that, she served as Director of Virginia Relations at the George Washington University. She previously served in Governor Tim Kaine's policy office.
    In addition to reviewing legislation (see Series I.B.6), O'Holleran focused on economic development, education, and energy issues. She also kept a series of notebooks, arranged chronologically, containing daily handwritten notes from meetings and to-do lists.
    - Alexandria's Combined Sewer System, 4 August 2017. (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - American Association of Motor Vehicle Administrators, Best Practices Guide to Reducing Suspended Drivers, 2013. (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Bon Air Elementary Leadership School, 2013. (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Boycott, Divestment and Sanctions (BDS), 2016. (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Cannabidiol (CBD), 2016. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Capitol One, 2017. (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Cato Institute, 2017. (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Commission on Diversity, Equity and Inclusion (Created by Executive Order 69), 2017. (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Commonwealth Institute, 2016- 2017. (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Communities in Schools, 2015. (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Council on Virginia's Future, 2015. (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Craig County Public Schools, 2014. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Dominion, 2015-2017. (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Education, 2015-2016. (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Energy, 2013-2016. (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Environmental Council of the States (ECOS), 2017. (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Governor's Cabinet Retreat, University of Virginia, 4-5 January 2017. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Handouts in support of legislation, undated. (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Healthcare, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Highland New Wind Development (HNWD), 2016. (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Jefferson Lab, October 2015. (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC), 2017. (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - LGBT Tourism Task Force, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Law Enforcement, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Medicare Participation Certification, 2014. (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Mental Illness in Jails, 2014; 2016. (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Military Family/Spouse Issues, undated. (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Misclassification Task Force, undated. (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - National Association of Social Workers of Virginia (NASW-VA), undated. (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - National Governors Association (NGA), Cyber Challenge, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Natural Resources, 2015; 2017. (Box 16, Folder 31)
    - Notebooks
      - Budget Development, September 2015-December 2015. (Box 16, Folder 32)
      - Daily Notes, November 2013-January 2014. (Box 16, Folder 33)
      - Daily Notes, January 2014-February 2014?. (Box 16, Folder 34)
      - Daily Notes (x2), undated (probably 2014-2015). (Box 16, Folder 35)
      - Daily Notes, December 2015-June 2016. (Box 16, Folder 36)
      - Daily Notes, July 2016. (Box 16, Folder 37)
      - Daily Notes, August 2016-November 2016. (Box 16, Folder 38)
      - Daily Notes, November 2016-March 2017. (Box 16, Folder 39)
      - Daily Notes, March 2017-October 2017. (Box 16, Folder 40)
    - One Stop Workforce and Education Center, The Improvement Association, 2015. (Box 16, Folder 41)
    - OpenGov, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 42)
    - Pew Charitable Trusts, State Strategies to Detect Local Fiscal Distress, 6 December 2016. (Box 16, Folder 43)
    - Public Safety, undated. (Box 16, Folder 44)
    - Rasier, LLC/Transportation Network Companies (TNC), January 2017. (Box 16, Folder 45)
    - Retirement, 2015. (Box 16, Folder 46)
    - Richmond International Raceway Redevelopment, December 2015. (Box 16, Folder 47)
    - Rivada Networks (public safety communications), undated. (Box 16, Folder 48)
    - School Discipline, 2015-2016. (Box 16, Folder 49)
    - Solar Policy Collaborative Workgroup, 2016. (Box 16, Folder 50)
    - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB), 2014. (Box 16, Folder 51)
    - State Corporation Commission, 2016-2017. (Box 16, Folder 52)
    - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia (SCHEV), 2017. (Box 16, Folder 53)
    - Strategic Priorities, 31 August 2015. (Box 16, Folder 54)
    - Stubhub, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Thomas Nelson Community College, 2014. (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - University of Virginia, undated. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Unpaid Court Fines, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Broadband Deployment Act, 2016. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Chamber of Commerce, 2014; 2016. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Virginia Commission for the Arts, 2016. (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Virginia Department of Alcoholic Beverage Control, 2016. (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Virginia Department of Criminal Justice Services, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Virginia Department of Education, 2015. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Virginia Department of Health, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Department of Medical Assistance Services, 2015; 2017. (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Virginia Economic Development Partnership (VEDP), 2016-2017. (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Virginia Education Association, undated. (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Virginia Employment Commission (VEC), Rapid Response, undated. (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Virginia Hospital and Healthcare Association, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Virginia Investment Pool Trust Fund (VIP), 2016. (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Virginia International Trade Corporation (VITC), 2016. (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Virginia Lottery, 2016. (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Virginia Management Fellows Program, undated. (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Virginia Maritime Association, 2014. (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Virginia Museum of Natural History, 2014. (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Virginia Parole Board, 2017. (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Virginia Retirement System (VRS), undated. (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Virginia School Board Association (VSBA), Report of the VSBA Task Force on Schools in Challenging Environments, October 2014. (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Virginia Sports and Entertainment Complex, undated. (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Virginia State Board of Elections (SBE), General Registrar/Electoral Board (GREB) Workgroup, 2017. (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Virginia Tech, 2014. (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Virginia Unmanned Systems (UMS) Commission, 2016. (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Virtual Virginia, 2016. (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Workforce Development, 2016. (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - YMCA, 2017. (Box 18, Folder 0)
  - Subseries II.D. Jay Swanson, Deputy Policy Director, 2008; 2014-2015., Extent: 1.28 cubic feet (3 boxes) (Box 19-22)
    This subseries is housed in three (3) boxes. The records were in no discernible order; a large number of records were loose and not foldered. The processing archivist imposed an alphabetical arrangement by subject. Jay Swanson served as Deputy Policy Director from January 2014 to July 2015. Swanson previously worked as a policy advisor on Terry McAuliffe's 2013 gubernatorial campaign. Swanson was assigned the following policy areas: agriculture and forestry, Natural Resources, Technology, and Transportation.
    - 100 Day Plan, 2014. (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Agriculture Bioscience, 2014. (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Agriculture and Forestry, 2014-2015. (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Bioscience, 2014. (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Briefings - Secretary of Natural Resources, 2014. (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Briefings: Secretary of Transportation Aubrey Layne/Governor Terry McAuliffe, 2014. (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Budget, 2014. (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Certificate of Recognition, Atlantic Menhaden, May 2015. (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Chesapeake Bay, 2014. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Climate Change Commission, 2008; 2014. (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Commonwealth Council on Bridging the Nutritional Divide, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Commonwealth Transportation Board (CTB) Speech, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Enrolled Bill Review (HB 650, HB 844, SB 145, SB 551 and SB 565, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Fort Monroe, 2015. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - General Assembly, 2015 Session, 2014-2015. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Governor Meetings, February 2015. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Hampton Roads Transit, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Hampton Roads Transportation Accountability Commission (HTAC), 2014. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - HB2/Transportation, 2015. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Land Preservation Tax Credit (LPTC)/Green Executive Orders, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Land Tax Credit, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Local Government, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Metro - Momentum Strategic Plan, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Natural Resources, 2014. (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Notebook, 10 September 2014-2 March 2015. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    - Norfolk, 2014. (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - P3/Ominibus, 2015. (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Silver Line, 2014. (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Strategic Plan, 2014. (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Technology, 2014. (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Transportation, 2014. (Box 22, Folder 6)